Guide to the Yasser Alwan Collection AD.MC.002
New York University Abu Dhabi Library
- Series II: Egypt, 1895-1971; 585 (Box 1-7)
  - Two women in hats, with a baby and a man in the background. 8.5 x 6.0 cm, Undated; cuid1000; 1433; Unknown (Box 5, Folder 12)
    Eye Glasses/Sunglasses; Hats; Children; Women; Men; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Egypt; Jewelry; Group Portraits; Caves; Facial Hair
  - Three women wearing hats. 7.4 x 5.0 cm, Undated; cuid1001; 1434; Unknown (Box 5, Folder 12)
    French Writing; Hats; Photographic Prints; Women; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; Egypt
  - Two boys in coats, standing next to a house (same boy from ref1030). 9.7 x 6.8 cm, Undated; cuid1002; 1435; Unknown (Box 5, Folder 12)
    Photographic Prints; Houses; Boys; Gelatin Silver Prints; Egypt; Children; Group Portraits
  - A man wearing traditional Upper Egyptian galabeya holding a boy's hand (same boy from ref1029). 9.7 x 7.0 cm, Undated; cuid1003; 1436; Unknown (Box 5, Folder 12)
    Egypt; Streets/Roads; Boys; Gelatin Silver Prints; Men; Eye Glasses/Sunglasses; Hats; Regional/National Dress; Bags/Purses; Photographic Prints; Cars/Trucks; Turbans; Group Portraits; Transportation; Boys; Children; Facial Hair; Hats
  - A group of men and women sitting on the Ramses II Sphynx in Mempis, Egypt. 8.6 x 11.5 cm, Undated; cuid1004; 1437; Unknown (Box 5, Folder 12)
    Memphis, Egypt; Hats; Women; Fezes/Tarbouches; Men; Group Portraits; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints
  - A man posing in a garden in Beni Suef (same man from ref974). 11.1 x 6.5 cm, 17 February 1937; cuid1005; 1438; Unknown (Box 5, Folder 12)
    Kiosks/Kushk; Individual Portraits; Photographic Prints; Parks; Gardens; Beni Suef, Egypt; Men; French Writing; Gelatin Silver Prints
  - A family group in a home setting. 6.5 x 6.5 cm, 23 June 1962; cuid1006; 1439; Unknown (Box 5, Folder 12)
    Arabic Writing; Houses; Egypt; Photographic Prints; Furnishings; Women; Men; Children; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; Facial Hair
  - A man in a light colored suit in front of a mirror. 7.0 x 9.7 cm, Undated; cuid1007; 1440; Unknown (Box 5, Folder 12)
    Gelatin Silver Prints; Men; Photographic Prints; Mirrors; Egypt; Houses; Individual Portraits; Furnishings
  - Two men in uniforms in the desert. 8.5 x 6.2 cm, Undated; cuid1008; 1441; Unknown (Box 5, Folder 13)
    Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Military/Soldiers; Uniforms; Deserts; Men; Unknown Locations; Group Portraits; Facial Hair; Deserts
  - A man in a suit standing in front of a classical statue, smoking a pipe. 8.6 x 6.1 cm, Undated; cuid1009; 1443; Unknown (Box 5, Folder 13)
    Parks; Smoking; Gelatin Silver Prints; Men; Photographic Prints; Statues/Sculptures; Egypt; Individual Portraits; Tobacco pipes; Outdoors
  - A woman seated on a couch in a silky dress, another person sits next to her, the photo is torn. 5.9 x 5.9 cm, Undated; cuid1010; 1444; Unknown (Box 5, Folder 13)
    Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Egypt; Jewelry; Women; Group Portraits
  - Three women with three children on a balcony. 6.0 x 8.7 cm, Undated; cuid1011; 1445; Unknown (Box 5, Folder 13)
    Children; Women; Buildings; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Egypt; Group Portraits
  - A woman with four children sitting on the grass. 6.1 x 7.5 cm, Circa summer 1946; cuid1012; 1446; Unknown (Box 5, Folder 13)
    Photographic Prints; Gardens; Gelatin Silver Prints; Children; Women; Arabic Writing; Sidi Bishr, Alexandria, Egypt; Group Portraits
  - A couple standing in front of a car. 4.9 x 6.0 cm, 1 October 1939; cuid1013; 1447; Unknown (Box 5, Folder 13)
    Egypt; Women; Gelatin Silver Prints; Men; Landscapes; Photographic Prints; Countryside/Rural; Cars/Trucks; Group Portraits; Transportation; Facial Hair
  - A woman riding a donkey, with a man and a woman standing nearby. 6.3 x 5.1 cm, Undated; cuid1014; 1448; Unknown (Box 5, Folder 13)
    Women; Animals; Donkeys; Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Umbrellas/Parasols; Photographic Prints; Countryside/Rural; Men; Group Portraits
  - Two young women (same women from ref1044). 5.7 x 5.8 cm, Undated; cuid1015; 1449; Unknown (Box 5, Folder 13)
    Women; Egypt; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits
  - Four women and a child having tea (same women from ref1043). 5.7 x 5.8 cm, Undated; cuid1016; 1450; Unknown (Box 5, Folder 13)
    Food; Egypt; Drinks/Beverages; Tea/Coffee; Photographic Prints; Women; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; Furnishings; Houses; Children
  - A woman holding a baby. 7.1 x 6.0 cm, Undated; cuid1017; 1451; Unknown (Box 5, Folder 14)
    Egypt; Children; Women; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Group Portraits
  - Five women posing in the garden. 8.8 x 7.2 cm, Undated; cuid1018; 1452; Unknown (Box 5, Folder 14)
    Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Women; Gardens; Group Portraits; Photographic Prints
  - Two women standing in front of the boat the "ΙΩΝΙΑ" with a Greek flag. 8.6 x 6.4 cm, Undated; cuid1019; 1453; Unknown (Box 5, Folder 14)
    Women; Flags; Photographic Prints; Boats/Ships; Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Boats/Ships; Greek Writing; Docks/Piers/Jetties; Group Portraits
  - A woman on a wooden porch. 8.9 x 5.9 cm, Undated; cuid1020; 1454; Unknown (Box 5, Folder 14)
    Individual Portraits; Photographic Prints; Women; Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints
  - A woman standing in front of the sea, in a spotted dress. 8.5 x 6.1 cm, UNdated; cuid1021; 1455; Unknown (Box 5, Folder 14)
    Individual Portraits; Photographic Prints; Seas; Beaches; Women; Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints
  - A family group posing with a motorcycle and sidecar on a street. 6.2 x 8.4 cm, Undated; cuid1022; 1456; Unknown (Box 5, Folder 14)
    Photographic Prints; Egypt; Streets/Roads; Motorcycles; Women; Gelatin Silver Prints; Men; Group Portraits; Transportation; Boys; Children; Bow Ties; Streets/Roads
  - Three women and a boy with a cat. 8.5 x 5.9 cm, Undated; cuid1023; 1457; Unknown (Box 5, Folder 14)
    Seas; Group Portraits; Gelatin Silver Prints; Egypt; Photographic Prints; Women; Cats; Animals; Boys; Children
  - A woman and a boy standing in front of a tearoom storefront. 6.1 x 9.0 cm, Undated; cuid1024; 1458; Unknown (Box 5, Folder 14)
    Streets/Roads; Restaurants/bars; Boys; Women; Shops; Children; Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Street Lamps; Group Portraits
  - A man sitting on a deckchair on a beach. 11.0 x 6.7 cm, 6 October 1937; cuid1025; 1459; Unknown (Box 5, Folder 14)
    Gelatin Silver Prints; Boats/Ships; Beaches; Men; Photographic Prints; Arabic Writing; Seas; Port Said, Egypt
  - A man in a suit, lying down on the edge of a small garden, in front of a gated property. 8.9 x 6.1 cm, Undated; cuid1026; 1460; Unknown (Box 5, Folder 14)
    Photographic Prints; Gardens; Men; Buildings; Individual Portraits; Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints
  - A young woman wearing a costume, sitting on a rooftop (same woman from ref1064). 8.9 x 5.9 cm, Undated; cuid1027; 1461; Unknown (Box 5, Folder 15)
    Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Regional/National Dress; Women; Individual Portraits; Egypt; Costumes
  - A woman in a halterneck dress standing in front of a mirrored sideboard. 8.8 x 6.1 cm, Undated; cuid1028; 1462; Unknown (Box 5, Folder 15)
    Photographic Prints; Mirrors; Gelatin Silver Prints; Women; Furnishings; Egypt; Houses; Individual Portraits; Carpets/Rugs
  - A woman sitting in a leather armchair. 8.8 x 6.4 cm, Undated; cuid1029; 1463; Unknown (Box 5, Folder 15)
    Furnishings; Individual Portraits; Jewelry; Clocks/Watches; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Egypt; Women
  - Two young women in black bathing on a houseboat. 11.0 x 8.2 cm, Undated; cuid1030; 1464; Unknown (Box 5, Folder 15)
    Egypt; Girls; Women; Bathing Suits/Swimsuits; Gelatin Silver Prints; Docks/Piers/Jetties; Photographic Prints; Group Portraits
  - A family group standing in front of a topiary pyramid (linked ref1060 and ref1061). 9.1 x 6.2 cm, Undated; cuid1031; 1465; Unknown (Box 5, Folder 15)
    Egypt; Parks; Boys; Women; Gelatin Silver Prints; Men; Outdoors; Gardens; Children; Photographic Prints; Group Portraits
  - A family group sitting at a table in front of a large palm tree (linked ref1059 and ref1061). 9.2 x 6.3 cm, Undated; cuid1032; 1466; Unknown (Box 5, Folder 15)
    Gardens; Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Parties; Group Portraits; Women; Boys; Children; Restaurants/bars
  - A boy standing in front of a fountain (linked ref1059and ref1060). 9.0 x 6.2 cm, Undated; cuid1033; 1467; Unknown (Box 5, Folder 15)
    Outdoors; Individual Portraits; Fountains; Egypt; Photographic Prints; Boys; Parks; Gelatin Silver Prints; Children
  - A woman and a boy on a balcony. 8.3 x 5.8 cm, Undated; cuid1034; 1468; Unknown (Box 5, Folder 15)
    Egypt; Photographic Prints; Boys; Women; Gelatin Silver Prints; Children; Group Portraits
  - An Egyptian man with a group of Western-looking people in a garden. 6.4 x 8.9 cm, Undated; cuid1035; 1469; Unknown (Box 5, Folder 15)
    Gardens; Photographic Prints; Men; Gelatin Silver Prints; Europe; Women; Houses; Smoking; Group Portraits; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares; Cigarettes; Outdoors
  - A woman wearing lots of jewelry, posing on a rooftop (same woman from ref1055). 8.9 x 6.0 cm, 17/3/1939; cuid1036; 1470; Unknown (Box 5, Folder 15)
    Women; Photographic Prints; Individual Portraits; Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Regional/National Dress; Jewelry; Arabic Writing; Head Covers/Veils
  - A large family group under a wooden trellis. 6.0 x 9.0 cm, Undated; cuid1037; 1471; Unknown (Box 5, Folder 16)
    Gardens; Children; Women; Men; Photographic Prints; Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; Facial Hair
  - A man standing in front of a crowd of people with a mosque in the background. 8.9 x 5.9 cm, Undated; cuid1038; 1472; Unknown (Box 5, Folder 15)
    Turbans; Crowds; Architecture; Buildings; Arabic Writing; Egypt; Men; Mosques; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Religious Sites
  - A man in white lab coat reading Al Ahram newspaper (linked ref824). 6.6 x 9.2 cm, Undated; cuid1039; 1473; Unknown (Box 5, Folder 16)
    Individual Portraits; Egypt; Men; Newspapers/Magazines; Eye Glasses/Sunglasses; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Lab Coats; Furnishings
  - A group pose in a garden, one girl wears a girl scouts/guides uniform. 6.6 x 9.6 cm, Undated; cuid1040; 1474; Unknown (Box 5, Folder 16)
    Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Gardens; Boys; Men; Uniforms; Scouts; Girls; Egypt; Children; Group Portraits
  - Four young men in bathing suits at the beach. 8.8 x 6.2 cm, 16 October 1920; cuid1041; 1475; Unknown (Box 5, Folder 16)
    Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Bathing Suits/Swimsuits; Beaches; Boys; Men; Greek Writing; Seas; Egypt; Children; Group Portraits
  - A woman petting a dog. 6.3 x 6.3 cm, Summer 1961; cuid1074; 1504; Unknown (Box 5, Folder 19)
    Animals; Egypt; English Writing; Individual Portraits; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Dogs; Women
  - Two couples mounted on bicycles. Names are written in French on the front. 6.0 x 8.5 cm, Undated; cuid1075; 1506; Unknown (Box 5, Folder 19)
    Bicycles/Tricycles; Group Portraits; Women; Men; French Writing; Group Portraits; Buildings; Gelatin Silver Prints; Egypt; Photographic Prints; Hats; Outdoors; Transportation
  - Two men working with factory machinery. 6.9 x 8.1 cm, Undated; cuid1076; 1509; Unknown (Box 5, Folder 19)
    Arabic Writing; Photographic Prints; Men; Factories; Workers; Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Machines
  - A man in suit with trees behind him. 7.3 x 10.2 cm, Undated; cuid1077; 1511; Unknown (Box 5, Folder 20)
    Outdoors; Photographic Prints; Men; Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Individual Portraits
  - A topless man. 10.5 x 7.5 cm, Undated; cuid1078; 1512; Unknown (Box 5, Folder 20)
    Men; Individual Portraits; Photographic Prints; Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints
  - A man having his teeth checked by a dentist. 6.5 x 9.2 cm, Undated; cuid1083; 1517; Unknown (Box 5, Folder 20)
    Unknown Locations; Gelatin Silver Prints; Men; Dentists; Photographic Prints
  - Postcard of an arrangement of flowers with French writing. Armenian writing on the reverse. "Dear Panos, while a little late, I sincerely congratulate you with the ocassion of New Year and Christmas. May the coming year bring you happiness and new successes. I will soon answer to your previous letters. Kisses." 13.6 x 8.9 cm, Undated; cuid1084; 1518; Unknown (Box 5, Folder 21)
    Unknown Locations; French Writing; Flower Garlands/Bouquets; Armenian Writing; Postcards; Hand-colored Photographs/Hand-tinting
  - Postcard of a naked woman with a pearl necklace, holding a flower. 13.7 x 8.7 cm, Undated; cuid1085; 1519; Unknown (Box 5, Folder 21)
    Jewelry; Postcards; Unknown Locations; Nude/Naked; Hand-colored Photographs/Hand-tinting; Women; Individual Portraits
  - Postcard of a naked woman with a pearl necklace, resting on a cushion. 13.7 x 8.6 cm, Undated; cuid1086; 1520; Unknown (Box 5, Folder 21)
    Jewelry; Nude/Naked; Women; Unknown Locations; Postcards; Hand-colored Photographs/Hand-tinting; Individual Portraits; Carpets/Rugs
  - Postcard of a girl in a pink dress, holding a basket of flowers. 13.7 x 8.8 cm, Undated; cuid1087; 1521; Unknown (Box 5, Folder 21)
    Individual Portraits; Painted Backdrops; Flower Garlands/Bouquets; Girls; Arabic Writing; Hand-colored Photographs/Hand-tinting; French Writing; Postcards; Children; Unknown Locations
  - Postcard of a boy in traditional dress sitting in a chair. 13.9 x 8.8 cm, Undated; cuid1109; 1543; Studio Abou Hashem, Sahel Al Ghelal, Giza (Egypt) (Box 5, Folder 23)
    Arabic Writing; Fezes/Tarbouches; Children; Photographic Prints; Postcards; Regional/National Dress; Boys; Unknown Locations; Hand-colored Photographs/Hand-tinting; Individual Portraits; Giza, Egypt
  - Postcard of a baby and basket of Easter eggs and flowers. French text "Happy Easter". 13.7 x 8.7 cm, 4 April 1926; cuid1110; 1544; Unknown (Box 5, Folder 23)
    Italian Writing; Photographic Prints; Unknown Locations; Postcards; Easter; Flower Garlands/Bouquets; Hand-colored Photographs/Hand-tinting; Individual Portraits; Children
  - Postcard of a girl and boy, leaning out a window. 13.6 x 8.7 cm, Undated; cuid1111; 1545; Unknown (Box 5, Folder 23)
    Flower Garlands/Bouquets; Hand-colored Photographs/Hand-tinting; Girls; Boys; Postcards; Unknown Locations; Group Portraits; Children
  - Postcard of a bride and groom. 13.6 x 8.7 cm, Undated; cuid1112; 1546; Unknown (Box 5, Folder 23)
    Arabic Writing; Photographic Prints; Men; Postcards; Women; Unknown Locations; Hand-colored Photographs/Hand-tinting; Group Portraits
  - Postcard of a woman holding flowers, whole postcard is tinted pink. Text in French "Happy Easter". 13.7 x 8.6 cm, Undated; cuid1113; 1547; Fotocelere (Turin, Italy); Unknown (Box 5, Folder 23)
    Postcards; Individual Portraits; Hand-colored Photographs/Hand-tinting; French Writing; Easter; Italy; Women; Flower Garlands/Bouquets; Jewelry; Photographic Prints; Unknown Locations
  - Postcard of a young man playing an oud in a garden. 14.0 x 8.8 cm, 15 August 1933; cuid1114; 1548; Unknown (Box 5, Folder 24)
    Postcards; Photographic Prints; Oud; Musical Instruments; Hand-colored Photographs/Hand-tinting; Men; Arabic Writing; Gardens; Unknown Locations; Individual Portraits
  - Postcard of a woman in a pink dress, with gloves. 13.8 x 9.0 cm, Undated; cuid1115; 1549; Unknown (Box 5, Folder 24)
    Unknown Locations; Individual Portraits; Photographic Prints; Painted Backdrops; Flower Garlands/Bouquets; Women; Postcards; Hand-colored Photographs/Hand-tinting
  - Postcard of a woman sitting on a chair with an embeddded image of a couple in the clouds. 13.6 x 8.7 cm, Undated; cuid1117; 1551; Unknown (Box 5, Folder 24)
    Countryside/Rural; Unknown Locations; Women; Hand-colored Photographs/Hand-tinting; Postcards; Men; Group Portraits
  - Postcard of a girl in pink with a flower basket. 13.8 x 8.7 cm, Undated; cuid1119; 1553; Unknown (Box 5, Folder 24)
    Unknown Locations; Individual Portraits; Hand-colored Photographs/Hand-tinting; Postcards; Flower Garlands/Bouquets; Girls; Children
  - Postcard of a girl in a yellow dress. 13.6 x 8.6 cm, Undated; cuid1121; 1555; Unknown (Box 5, Folder 24)
    Postcards; Photographic Prints; Individual Portraits; Flower Garlands/Bouquets; Girls; Unknown Locations; Hand-colored Photographs/Hand-tinting; Children
  - Postcard of a woman wearing a purple hat. French text "Happy New Year". 13.5 x 8.7 cm, Undated; cuid1122; 1556; Unknown (Box 5, Folder 24)
    Hand-colored Photographs/Hand-tinting; Hats; Unknown Locations; Individual Portraits; Jewelry; Photographic Prints; Postcards; French Writing; Women
  - Postcard of a village scene in winter. French Text "Happy New Year". 13.7 x 8.6 cm, Undated; cuid1123; 1557; Unknown (Box 5, Folder 24)
    Countryside/Rural; French Writing; Postcards; Unknown Locations; Flower Garlands/Bouquets; Buildings; Hand-colored Photographs/Hand-tinting
  - Postcard of a couple hand in hand. 13.6 x 8.4 cm, Undated; cuid1124; 1558; Unknown (Box 5, Folder 24)
    Women; Men; Unknown Locations; Hand-colored Photographs/Hand-tinting; Postcards; Group Portraits
  - A group of men in front of a picture of King Fuad (linked ref1156). 33.8 x 40.0 cm, 1 September 1930; cuid1125; 1559; Studio Photo Varjabedian, Zagazig, Egypt (Box 6, Folder 1, Oversize unknown container)
    Photographic Prints; Carpets/Rugs; Boys; Men; Group Portraits; Zagazig, Egypt; Fezes/Tarbouches; Gelatin Silver Prints; Studio Photography; Children; Furnishings; Facial Hair
  - Men standing on the steps of a building. 34.3 x 40.5 cm, cuid1126; 1560; Unknown (Box 6, Folder 1, Oversize unknown container)
    Arabic Writing; Egypt; Signatures; Men; Buildings; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Fezes/Tarbouches; Group Portraits; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares; Facial Hair
  - A group of men, some with military uniforms, outside a building. 30.4 x 44.5 cm, Undated; cuid1127; 1561; Unknown (Box 6, Folder 1, Oversize unknown container)
    Uniforms; Military/Soldiers; Men; Fezes/Tarbouches; Photographic Prints; Group Portraits; Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares; Medals/Insignia; Facial Hair
  - Men in suits, in front of a portrait of King Fuad (linked ref1153). 35.8 x 41.5 cm, Undated; cuid1128; 1562; Studio A. Rocca Photographe, Zagazig, Egypte (Box 6, Folder 1, Oversize unknown container)
    Gelatin Silver Prints; Zagazig, Egypt; Fezes/Tarbouches; Men; Group Portraits; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Carpets/Rugs; Furnishings; Facial Hair
  - Six men in suits pose in a garden. 32.8 x 44.0 cm, Undated; cuid1129; 1563; Studio Zola, Cairo (Egypt) (Box 6, Folder 1, Oversize unknown container)
    Men; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Group Portraits; Cairo, Egypt; Fezes/Tarbouches; Signatures; Buildings; Canes/Walking Sticks; Facial Hair; Gardens; Parks
  - A large group of men, with Egyptian flags in the background (linked ref1159). 33.3 x 39.9 cm, Circa 1923-1952; cuid1130; 1564; Studio - Kalil Akle (Box 6, Folder 2, Oversize unknown container)
    Gelatin Silver Prints; Fezes/Tarbouches; Flags; Uniforms; Military/Soldiers; Men; Group Portraits; Photographic Prints; Egypt; Canes/Walking Sticks; Facial Hair
  - A group of men pose outside a building. Arabic text on reverse: Mohamed Effendi Chadi (linked ref1158). 34.3 x 41.5 cm, 13 November 1934; cuid1131; 1565; Studio - Kalil Akle (Box 6, Folder 2, Oversize unknown container)
    Buildings; Men; Fezes/Tarbouches; Flags; Group Portraits; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Arabic Writing; Egypt; Regional/National Dress; Facial Hair
  - A group of men outside an ornate building with Arabic calligraphy on it (linked ref1161). Arabic text on front: Abdul Majid Effendi Mohammad - Gift from his colleagues. 33.9 x 40.5 cm, 19 June 1938; cuid1132; 1566; Studio Kofler, Cairo, Egypt (Box 6, Folder 2, Oversize unknown container)
    Architecture; Buildings; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; Men; Cairo, Egypt; Photographic Prints; Arabic Writing; Fezes/Tarbouches; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares; Facial Hair; Arabic Calligraphy
  - A group of men standing in front of a large building (linked ref1160). Arabic text on front: Abdul Majid Effendi Mohammad - Gift from his colleagues. Visit of General Prosecutor, Labib Beg Attiyya. Visit to city of Luxor, Egypt. 33.4 x 41.1 cm, 19 May 1935; cuid1133; 1567; Unknown (Box 6, Folder 2, Oversize unknown container)
    Men; Buildings; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; Fezes/Tarbouches; Photographic Prints; Arabic Writing; Luxor, Egypt; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares; Facial Hair
  - A group of men, some in military uniforms, in front of a building. 33.9 x 40.8 cm, Undated; cuid1134; 1568; Studio C. Zaphir, Tantah (Egypt) (Box 6, Folder 2, Oversize unknown container)
    Men; Uniforms; Military/Soldiers; Buildings; Group Portraits; Tanta/Tantah, Egypt; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Fezes/Tarbouches; Tanta/Tantah, Egypt; Boys; Children; Medals/Insignia; Facial Hair
  - Twelve men in suits and tarbouches, outside a building lined with hedges. 34.0 x 40.8 cm, Undated; cuid1135; 1569; Unknown (Box 6, Folder 3, Oversize unknown container)
    Group Portraits; Buildings; Men; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Egypt; Fezes/Tarbouches; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares; Facial Hair
  - A man in military uniform posing with men wearing gallabeyas and turbans. 36.0 x 41.7 cm, Undated; cuid1136; 1570; Unknown (Box 6, Folder 3, Oversize unknown container)
    Men; Regional/National Dress; Group Portraits; Uniforms; Military/Soldiers; Photographic Prints; Buildings; Turbans; Gelatin Silver Prints; Egypt; Facial Hair
  - A group of men in suits posing in a garden. 35.8 x 39.5 cm, Undated; cuid1137; 1571; Studio Al Chark, Tanta (Egypt) (Box 6, Folder 3, Oversize unknown container)
    Group Portraits; Gelatin Silver Prints; Men; Photographic Prints; Buildings; Tanta/Tantah, Egypt; Fezes/Tarbouches; Tanta/Tantah, Egypt; Facial Hair
  - Men in suits posing outside a building. Arabic text on front. "Jalal Beg Judge of Abnoub. On the occasion of his transfer to Assiout." 35.8 x 11.8 cm, December 1933; cuid1138; 1572; Unknown (Box 6, Folder 3, Oversize unknown container)
    Group Portraits; Fezes/Tarbouches; Buildings; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Arabic Writing; Asyut, Egypt; Men; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares; Facial Hair
  - Former Egyptian President Gamal Abdel Nasser and large group of men and women. Arabic text on reverse: "Alexandria Safa Palace. Nasser Arab Representative - Conference" 33.7 x 43.5 cm, August 1966; cuid1139; 1573; Unknown (Box 6, Folder 3, Oversize unknown container)
    Photographic Prints; Fezes/Tarbouches; Alexandria, Egypt; Nasser, Gamal Abdel; Men; Political Leadership; Women; Architecture; Buildings; Arabic Writing; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; Palaces; Facial Hair; Officials
  - A group of men outside a stone work building with two Pharaonic statues behind them. 34.0 x 40.9 cm, Undated; cuid1140; 1576; English Photo Stores, Mohamed Aboudi (Luxor, Egypt) (Box 6, Folder 4, Oversize unknown container)
    Luxor, Egypt; Statues/Sculptures; Egypt; Buildings; Men; Fezes/Tarbouches; Group Portraits; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Facial Hair
  - A group of men posing in a garden. Arabic text on front. "Employees of the Accounting Department". 39.0 x 42.6 cm, 5 September 1929; cuid1141; 1577; Studio Charles, Cairo (Egypt) (Box 6, Folder 4, Oversize unknown container)